A Guide to the Harry F. Byrd Jr. Papers
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series IV: Administration Files
  - Administration: Closing of Senator Byrd's Office, 1982 (Box Box 530)
  - Administration: Jack Davis, 1978-1981; (2 folders) (Box Box 530)
  - Administration: Form Letters, 1976-1979 (Box Box 530)
  - Administration: Franking Privilege, 1973-1976 (Box Box 530)
  - Administration: General Consideration, 1973; (2 folders) (Box Box 530)
  - Administration: General Consideration, 1974, 1975 August-December; (7 folders) (Box Box 531)
  - Administration: General Consideration, 1975 January-July, 1976; (6 folders) (Box Box 532)
  - Administration: General Consideration, 1977; (7 folders) (Box Box 533)
  - Administration: General Consideration, 1978; (6 folders) (Box Box 534)
  - Administration: General Consideration, 1979; (6 folders) (Box Box 535)
  - Administration: General Consideration, 1980; (6 folders) (Box Box 536)
  - Administration: General Consideration, 1981 April-December; (7 folders) (Box Box 537)
  - Administration: General Consideration, 1981 January-March, 1982 March 19-31, April-December; (6 folders) (Box Box 538)
  - Administration: General Consideration, 1982 January-March 1-18; (5 folders) (Box Box 539)
  - Administration: Memoranda, 1970-1978 (Box Box 539)
  - Administration: Memoranda from Phil Reberger to Staff, 1974-1976 (Box Box 539)
  - Administration: Memoranda from the Staff to Phil Reberger, 1974-1975 (Box Box 539)
  - Administration: Memoranda from Forrest Rettgers, 1968-1970 (Box Box 539)
  - Administration: Memoranda from George Shanks, 1973; (3 folders) (Box Box 540)
  - Administration: Memoranda from Ed White, 1971-1972 (Box Box 540)
  - Administration: Questionnaires, 1976-1980 (Box Box 540)
  - Administration: Shuffling Duty Schedule, 1974-1977 (Box Box 540)
  - Administration: White House Nominations, 1973-1976, 1977 March-December; (3 folders) (Box Box 540)
  - Administration: White House Nominations, 1977 January-February, 1978-1982; (7 folders) (Box Box 541)
- Series V: Personal Papers
  - Personal, 1970-1972; (8 folders) (Box Box 542)
  - Personal, 1973-1974, 1975 September-December; (7 folders) (Box Box 543)
  - Personal, 1975 January-August, 1976; (9 folders) (Box Box 544)
  - Personal, 1977-1979; (8 folders) (Box Box 545)
  - Personal, 1980-1982; (2 folders) (Box Box 546)
  - Personal: Jack Anderson - Column, 1976; (3 folders) (Box Box 546)
  - Personal: Biographic Material, 1966-1970, 1982 (Box Box 546)
  - Personal: Byrd Business, 1970, 1971 July-December; (2 folders) (Box Box 546)
  - Personal: Byrd Business, 1971 January-June, 1972; (3 folders) (Box Box 547)
  - Personal: Byrd Family, 1954-1977; (6 folders) (Box Box 547)
  - Personal: Byrd Family, 1978-1982; (2 folders) (Box Box 548)
  - Personal: Caricatures of Political Figures by MacNelly, n.d. (Box Box 548)
  - Personal: Certificates, 1970-1982, n.d. (Box Box 548)
  - Personal: "Expedition to St. Brandon's" compiled by Lewis H. Strauss, 1976-1977 (Box Box 548)
  - Personal: Guest Books, 1975-1981; (3 volumes) (Box Box 548)
  - Personal: London Trip, 1980 (Box Box 549)
  - Personal: Newsclippings, 1974-1982 (Box Box 549)
  - Personal: Photographs, 1966-1982, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 549)
  - Personal: South Pole Trip, 1979-1980; (4 folders) (Box Box 549)
- Series VI: Publicity
  - Publicity, 1975-1982 (Box Box 550)
  - Publicity: Bert Minor, 1977 (Box Box 550)
  - Publicity: Meet the Press, 1979 (Box Box 550)
  - Publicity: Newsletter Response, 1973 June 19-December; (6 folders) (Box Box 550)
  - Publicity: Newsletter Response, 1973 January-June 1-18, 1974 August-December; (7 folders) (Box Box 551)
  - Publicity: Newsletter Response, 1974 February-July, 1975-1976; (7 folders) (Box Box 552)
  - Publicity: Newsletter Response, 1977, 1978 November-December; (6 folders) (Box Box 553)
  - Publicity: Newsletter Response, 1978 January-October, 1979; (7 folders) (Box Box 554)
  - Publicity: Newsletter Response, 1980-1982; (7 folders) (Box Box 555)
  - Publicity: Press Correspondence, 1973 (Box Box 555)
  - Publicity: Press Correspondence, 1974-1975, 1976 June-December; (7 folders) (Box Box 556)
  - Publicity: Press Correspondence, 1976 January-May, 1977-1979; (7 folders) (Box Box 557)
  - Publicity: Press Correspondence, 1980-1982; (4 folders) (Box Box 558)
  - Publicity: Press Correspondence - Lindbergh, 1974 (Box Box 558)
  - Publicity: Press Requests, 1974-1975; (2 folders) (Box Box 558)
  - Publicity: Press Requests, 1976-1978; (2 folders) (Box Box 559)
  - Publicity: Press - Senator, 1974, 1975 August-December; (5 folders) (Box Box 559)
  - Publicity: Press - Senator, 1975 January-July (Box Box 560)
  - Publicity: Radio & Television, 1973-1976 (Box Box 560)
  - Publicity: Subscriptions & Press Clippings, 1973-1979 (Box Box 560)
- Series VII: Public Activities
  - Public Activities: Annie J. Bronson Charitable Foundation, 1971-1981 (Box Box 560)
  - Public Activities: Appointment Book, 1978 (Box Box 560)
  - Public Activities: Appointments, 1972-1974; (4 folders) (Box Box 560)
  - Public Activities: Appointments, 1975-1976; (8 folders) (Box Box 561)
  - Public Activities: Appointments, 1977, 1978 April-December; (7 folders) (Box Box 562)
  - Public Activities: Appointments, 1978 January-March, 1979, 1980 June-December; (7 folders) (Box Box 563)
  - Public Activities: Appointments, 1980 January-May, 1981; (6 folders) (Box Box 564)
  - Public Activities: Appointments, 1982; (3 folders) (Box Box 565)
  - Public Activities: Harry F. Byrd, Sr. Papers at the University of Virginia, 1973-1982; (3 folders) (Box Box 565)
  - Public Activities: Harry F. Byrd, Jr. Papers at the University of Virginia, 1978 (Box Box 565)
  - Public Activities: Campaign Invitations and Questionnaires, 1976 (Box Box 565)
  - Public Activities: Congressional Record Inserts by Senator Byrd, 1974-1977 (Box Box 565)
  - Public Activities: Donations, 1972-1981; (8 folders) (Box Box 566)
  - Public Activities: Election Congratulations, 1976 November-December, 1977; (7 folders) (Box Box 567)
  - Public Activities: Honorary Memberships, Board of Trustees, Sponsor, etc., 1976-1982 (Box Box 568)
  - Public Activities: Inauguration Tickets, 1976, 1980-1981 (Box Box 568)
  - Public Activities: Invitations Accepted, 1973 March-December; (6 folders) (Box Box 568)
  - Public Activities: Invitations Accepted, 1973 January-February, 1974 May-December; (6 folders) (Box Box 569)
  - Public Activities: Invitations Accepted, 1974 January-April, 1975 September-December; (5 folders) (Box Box 570)
  - Public Activities: Invitations Accepted, 1975 January-July, 1976 October-December; (6 folders) (Box Box 571)
  - Public Activities: Invitations Accepted, 1976 April-September; (5 folders) (Box Box 572)
  - Public Activities: Invitations Accepted, 1976 January-March, 1977 May-December; (7 folders) (Box Box 573)
  - Public Activities: Invitations Accepted, 1977 January-April, 1978 September-December; (5 folders) (Box Box 574)
  - Public Activities: Invitations Accepted, 1978 January-August; (5 folders) (Box Box 575)
  - Public Activities: Invitations Accepted, 1979 March-December; (6 folders) (Box Box 576)
  - Public Activities: Invitations Accepted, 1979 January-February, 1980 May-December; (5 folders) (Box Box 577)
  - Public Activities: Invitations Accepted, 1980 January-April, 1981 October-December; (5 folders) (Box Box 578)
  - Public Activities: Invitations Accepted, 1981 May-September; (4 folders) (Box Box 579)
  - Public Activities: Invitations Accepted, 1981 January-April, 1982 September-December; (6 folders) (Box Box 580)
  - Public Activities: Invitations Accepted, 1982 January-August; (6 folders) (Box Box 581)
  - Public Activities: Invitations Accepted - Alexandria Junior Woman's Club, 1976, 1979-1981; (2 folders) (Box Box 582)
  - Public Activities: Invitations Accepted - Southwest Virginia Trip, 1974 (Box Box 582)
  - Public Activities: Invitations from Senator Byrd, 1973-1982 (Box Box 582)
  - Public Activities: Invitations - Open, 1973-1975; (3 folders) (Box Box 582)
  - Public Activities: Invitations - Open, 1976-1982; (3 folders) (Box Box 583)
  - Public Activities: Letters of Introduction from Senator Byrd, 1973-1977 (Box Box 583)
  - Public Activities: Memorabilia - Bicentennial Flags, ca. 1976 (Box Box 583)
  - Public Activities: Memorabilia - First Day Covers, 1973-1982 (Box Box 583)
  - Public Activities: Memorabilia - Medallions & Commemorative Coins, 1968-1980 (Box Box 583)
  - Public Activities: Memorabilia - Miscellaneous, 1970, 1975-1976, n.d.; (2 folders) (Box Box 584)
  - Public Activities: Memorabilia - Presidential Ceremonial Pens, 1979, 1981 (Box Box 584)
  - Public Activities: Schedule, 1974-1976, 1980 (Box Box 584)
  - Public Activities: Speaker Requests, 1973; (3 folders) (Box Box 584)
  - Public Activities: Speaker Requests, 1974-1982; (5 folders) (Box Box 585)
  - Public Activities: Travel - Airline Reservations, 1979-1981 (Box Box 585)
  - Public Activities: VIP Correspondence - A-By, 1971-1982; (3 folders) (Box Box 585)
    Correspondents include: Hank Aaron, David C. Acheson, Spiro Agnew, Lindsay Almond, Mayor Marion S. Barry, William C. Battle, Lloyd Bentsen, W. Michael Blumenthal, William F. Bolger, Daniel J. Boorstin, J.S.F. Botha, Chester Bowles, Patrick Buchanan, James L. Buckley (with his maiden speech, April 20, 1971), Warren E. Burger, and George Bush
  - Public Activities: VIP Correspondence - C-Ma, 1968-1982; (8 folders) (Box Box 586)
    Correspondents include: Joseph A. Califano, James Callaghan, Johnny Carriger (songwriter of Virginia is for Lovers), Jimmy Carter, William J. Casey, John B. Connally, John Warren Cooke, Robert Cranborne, Rowley Cromer, Virginius Dabney, John N. Dalton, Simcha Dinitz (Israeli Ambassador), Raymond J. Donovan, James B. Edwards, Julie Eisenhower, Melih Esenbel (Turkish Ambassador), Douglas Fairbanks, Jr., Jerry Falwell, James Farley, Gerald R. Ford, Henry Ford II, B.G. Fourie (South African Ambassador), Vasco Vieira Garin (Portugese Ambassador), Arthur Godfrey, Mills E. Godwin, Jr., Barry Goldwater, Albert Gore, Sr., Alan Greenspan, Gilbert M. Grosvenor, Armand Hammer, W. Averell Harriman, Ali Hedda (Tunisian Ambassador), Linwood Holton, Hubert H. Humphrey, Muriel Humphrey, Lyndon Baines Johnson, Clarence M. Kelley, James J. Kilpatrick, Henry A. Kissinger, Edward I. Koch, Melvin R. Laird, Henry Luce III, Mike Mansfield, and John O. Marsh, Jr.
  - Public Activities: VIP Correspondence - Mc-Z, 1966-1982; (8 folders) (Box Box 587)
    Correspondents include: Frank McCarthy, George McGovern, Edwin Meese, Walter F. Mondale, Hans J. Morgenthau, Roger Mudd, Edmund S. Muskie, Paul H. Nitze, Richard M. Nixon, Frederick R. Nolting, Jr., Sandra D. O'Connor, Charlton Ogburn, Shimon Peres, Lewis F. Powell, Jr., Donald T. Regan, William H. Rehnquist, J. Sargeant Reynolds (speech, April 21, 1971), Eliot L. Richardson, Charles S. Robb, Oral Roberts, Pat Robertson, Nelson Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, William P. Rogers, Jane Russell, William Saxbe, James R. Schlesinger, Richard S. Schweiker, James C.H. Shen (Ambassador, Republic of China), George P. Schultz, William E. Simon, Howard K. Smith, Margaret Chase Smith, D.B. Sole (South African Ambassador), Berndt Von Staden (Federal Republic of Germany Ambassador), George Stevens, Jr., Sir John Stevens, Lewis H. Strauss, Robert S. Strauss, James D. Theberge (Nicaraguan Ambassador), Kenneth W. Thompson, Fumihiko Togo (Japanese Ambassador), John Tower, William M. Tuck, Stansfield Turner, John Warner, William H. Webster, W.C. Westmoreland, Murat Williams, Ardeshir Zahedi (Iranian Ambassador), and Elmo Zumwalt, Jr.
  - Public Activities: Visitors, 1972-1981; (6 folders) (Box Box 588)
- Series VIII: Miscellaneous Papers
  - Subseries A: Cassette Tapes
    - "On Economic Issues" by Peter F. Drucker, Westinghouse Learning Corporation, with printed script, 1976; T-931
    - "Kin & Communities" Sixth International Symposium of the Smithsonian Institution, Hubert Humphrey Reflects on Family Life and Other Words from the Opening Ceremony, Introduction by S. Dillon Ripley, Remarks by Mrs. Jimmy Carter, Mrs. Walter Washington, Alex Haley, and Margaret Mead, Music by the McLain Family Band, with printed biographies and a bibliography, 1978; T-932
    - "Meet the Member" with Senator Byrd, aired three times a week on WMAL-AM, Radio 63, Washington, D.C., 1979 January 8; T-933
    - "Dr. Charles Malik Questions & Answers," Bill Bright of Campus Crusade for Christ conducts a question and answer session on foreign policy with Malik, a professor in Beirut and the ambassador from Lebanon to the United Nations, ca. 1979; T-934
    - An Address by Harry F. Byrd, Jr., at the Fork Union Military Academy Upper School Graduation Exercises, 1982 May 29; T-935
    - "Meet the Member" with Senator Byrd, aired on WMAL-AM, Radio 63, Washington, D.C., profiling his career, 1982 August 18; T-936
    - Senator Byrd appeared as the "Guest Conductor" on the WGMS-RKO Radio Station, Rockville, Maryland, supported by the Standard Oil Company, 1982 November 7; T-937
  - Daily Carbons, 1973-1982; (50 Cubics)
    - "A" - "Day" 1973 [January. 31] - 1973 [December. 31] (Box 31)
    - "Day" - "Hic" 1973 [January. 31] - 1973 [December. 31] (Box 32)
    - "Hid" - "Mag" 1973 [January. 31] - 1973 [December. 31] (Box 33)
    - "Mah" - "Pugh" 1973 [January. 31] - 1973 [December. 31] (Box 34)
    - "Pur" - "Sz" 1973 [January. 31] - 1973 [December. 31] (Box 35)
    - "T" - "Z" 1973 [January. 31] - 1973 [December. 31] (Box 36)
    - "A" - "Bl" 1974 [January. 1] - 1974 [December. 31] (Box 36)
    - "Boa" - "Fin" 1974 [January. 1] - 1974 [December. 31] (Box 37)
    - "Fio" - "Kez" 1974 [January. 1] - 1974 [December. 31] (Box 38)
    - "Kh" - "Paf" 1974 [January. 1] - 1974 [December. 31] (Box 39)
    - "Pag" - "Tc" 1974 [January. 1] - 1974 [December. 31] (Box 40)
    - "To" - "Z" 1974 [January. 1] - 1974 [December. 31] (Box 41)
    - "A" - "Bj" 1975 [January. 1] - 1975 [December. 31] (Box 41)
    - "Bl" - "Doz" 1975 [January. 1] - 1975 [December. 31] (Box 42)
    - "Dr" - "Hol" 1975 [January. 1] - 1975 [December. 31] (Box 43)
    - "Hon" - "March" 1975 [January. 1] - 1975 [December. 31] (Box 44)
    - "March" - "Rob" 1975 [January. 1] - 1975 [December. 31] (Box 45)
    - "Rob"- "Wal" 1975 [January. 1] - 1975 [December. 31] (Box 46)
    - "Wal" - "Z" 1975 [January. 1] - 1975 [December. 31] (Box 47)
    - "A" - "Bra" 1976 [January. 1] - 1976 [December. 31] (Box 47)
    - "Bre" - "Fay" 1976 [January. 1] - 1976 [December. 31] (Box 48)
    - "Fez" - "It" 1976 [January. 1] - 1976 [December. 31] (Box 49)
    - "Iu" - "Miller" 1976 [January. 1] - 1976 [December. 31] (Box 50)
    - "Miller" - "Ruz" 1976 [January. 1] - 1976 [December. 31] (Box 51)
    - "Ry" - "Wh" 1977 [January. 1] - 1977 [December. 31] (Box 52)
    - "White" - "Z" 1977 [January. 1] - 1977 [December. 31] (Box 53)
    - "A" - "Ce" 1977 [January. 1] - 1977 [December. 31] (Box 53)
    - "Cf" - "Gi" 1977 [January. 1] - 1977 [December. 31] (Box 54)
    - "Gm" - "Lc" 1977 [January. 1] - 1977 [December. 31] (Box 55)
    - "La" - "Pe" 1977 [January. 1] - 1977 [December. 31] (Box 56)
    - "Pf" - "Tg" 1977 [January. 1] - 1977 [December. 31] (Box 57)
    - "Th" - "Z" 1977 [January. 1] - 1977 [December. 31] (Box 58)
    - "A" - "Be" 1978 [January. 1] - 1978 [December. 31] (Box 58)
    - "Be" - "Fi" 1978 [January. 1] - 1978 [December. 31] (Box 59)
    - "Fj" - "Kt" 1978 [January. 1] - 1978 [December. 31] (Box 60)
    - "Ku" - "Pk" 1978 [January. 1] - 1978 [December. 31] (Box 61)
    - "Pl" - "Vb" 1978 [January. 1] - 1978 [December. 31] (Box 62)
    - "Vc" - "Z" 1978 [January. 1] - 1978 [December. 31] (Box 63)
    - "A" - "Ca" 1979 [January. 1] - 1979 [December. 31] (Box 63)
    - "Cb" - "Gw" 1979 [January. 1] - 1979 [December. 31] (Box 64)
    - "Hb" - "McL" 1979 [January. 1] - 1979 [December. 31] (Box 65)
    - "McM" - "Rz" 1979 [January. 1] - 1979 [December. 31] (Box 66)
    - "S" - "Z" 1979 [January. 1] - 1979 [December. 31] (Box 67)
    - "A" - "Ej" 1980 [January. 1] - 1980 [December. 31] (Box 68)
    - "Ek" - "Jr" 1980 [January. 1] - 1980 [December. 31] (Box 69)
    - "Js" - "Pa" 1980 [January. 1] - 1980 [December. 31] (Box 70)
    - "Pb" - "Uz" 1980 [January. 1] - 1980 [December. 31] (Box 71)
    - "V" - "Z" 1980 [January. 1] - 1980 [December. 31] (Box 72)
    - "A" - "Bz" 1981 [January. 1] - 1981 [December. 31] (Box 72)
    - "C" - "Gt" 1981 [January. 1] - 1981 [December. 31] (Box 73)
    - "Gu" - "Mh" 1981 [January. 1] - 1981 [December. 31] (Box 74)
    - "McA" - "Sc" 1981 [January. 1] - 1981 [December. 31] (Box 75)
    - "Se" - "Z" 1981 [January. 1] - 1981 [December. 31] (Box 76)
    - "A" - "F" 1982 [January. 1] - 1982 [December. 31] (Box 77)
    - "G" - "Mi" 1982 [January. 1] - 1982 [December. 31] (Box 78)
    - "Mj" - "Tr" 1982 [January. 1] - 1982 [December. 31] (Box 79)
    - "Ts" - "Z" 1982 [January. 1] - 1982 [December. 31] (Box 80)
  - Subseries C: Oversize Material
    - American Revolution Bicentennial Certificate of Appreciation accorded to Honorable Harry F. Byrd, Jr. signed by John W. Warner and Jean McKee, 1976 (Box Oversize)
    - Color photograph of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. and King Hussein I of Jordan, signed "To my good friend Senator Harry F. Byrd, Jr., with my best wishes," with a letter, March 30, 1892, from the Ambassador of Jordan, Abdul Hadi Majali, 1982 (Box Oversize)
  - Subseries D: Card Tray #71
    - 3 x 5 index cards with the filing categories in use in Byrd's office after 1972, when the filing system changed, ca. 1972-1982